<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-15T19:26:49+06:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Yeff Blogs</title><subtitle>My blogging site, for me to write epic blogs on programming and programming related things</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Orbital and my Plans for it</title><link href="/2021/04/15/orbital-and-my-plans-for-it.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orbital and my Plans for it" /><published>2021-04-15T00:00:00+06:00</published><updated>2021-04-15T00:00:00+06:00</updated><id>/2021/04/15/orbital-and-my-plans-for-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/04/15/orbital-and-my-plans-for-it.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-orbital&quot;&gt;What is Orbital?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orbital is a 2D game engine im working on, written in the Java programming language. I mean for it to be a simple game engine/framework for game developers to be able to make small game prototypes quickly, but also make bigger games, while still keeping the codebase nice and simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-java&quot;&gt;Why Java?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a question im assuming a few people will ask. Why use Java, and not a lang like C/C++, which is much faster and much more commonly used for something like game engine dev? Well, firstly, I like Java. I learnt Java not too long back, but im a huge fan of Java’s syntax and just like using it in general, unlike something like C++, which I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;, and I used to enjoy it, but now I dont (preferences huh). Secondly, I tried C/C++ already. The first iteration of Orbital was written in C++ and DirectX, but I soon stopped on that because 1. DirectX is pain 2. Im bad at C++. Java was my first choice because 1. A friend of mine, Lucas Z (check out his github &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lucasstarsz&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; btw) is making a Java game engine called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lucasstarsz/FastJ&quot;&gt;FastJ&lt;/a&gt; as well, and he inspired me quite a bit. In fact, the current version of Orbital even uses the same graphics api (Java2D) as FastJ! 2. Java is still quite a popular language for game development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, my goals for projects are usually way too big for my skill level, so I had to do some consideration about my goals for Orbital. At first, back when I was writing Orbital in C++, I meant for the engine to be a powerful, industry-standard 3D and 2D engine, like Unity and Unreal. But I soon realized that something like that is waaaay to out of scope for me. So, I went for something smaller and simpler. I want Orbital to be a 2D engine which is simple to use. My main focus at this point is on simplicity. People should be able to just fire up a new project, type like 4 or 5 lines of code and get a basic window fired up. Simplicty is the &lt;strong&gt;key&lt;/strong&gt; part of Orbital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think thats all I have to say about Orbital for now. Any updates on Orbital will probably be found here in a new blog post. I hope you enjoyed reading this blog, have a good day! :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What is Orbital? Orbital is a 2D game engine im working on, written in the Java programming language. I mean for it to be a simple game engine/framework for game developers to be able to make small game prototypes quickly, but also make bigger games, while still keeping the codebase nice and simple.</summary></entry></feed>